

# Anand Kashyap

# **Professional Summary**

Data scientist with 4 Years of experience leveraging statistical modelling, data visualization, data processing, machine learning algorithms to solve challenging business problems. Total overall 7+ years of extensive experience in various platforms like Data Science, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Cloud and Infrastructure Services.

### **Projects**

- Spam Email Detection using classification techniques
- Thyroid detection
- Cement Strength

### Work History

# Harman International (A Samsung Company) – Senior Engineer Client: IRI (Analytics)

Bangalore, Karnataka 07/2017 - Current

- Experience in Data Analysis, visualization, statistics, programming and Machine Learning techniques.
- Extensive Model building experience with Machine Learning algorithms for Product
- Experience in creating mature Data science pipelines encompassing Data standardization, Feature extraction, model validation and optimization
- Exploring and visualizing data to drive insights
- Importing data from various sources and using numerous APIs
- Experienced in feature selection using filter methods, wrapper methods, Embedded methods and feature importance.
- Advance knowledge of ML algorithms such as Ensemble Models, Adaboost, Gradient-Boosting, Kernel-KNN, Grid search,
  Random Forest, Decision Tree, SVM, Linear Regression, Ridge, Lasso,
  Pipeline, Feature Union, Cross Validation, KFold.
- Extensive knowledge and implementation experience in XGBoost algorithm

# *anandkashyap*4711@*gmail.com* +91-9591030711/9902243911

Bengaluru, KA 560087

#### Technical -Skills

Machine Learning- Data Analysis, Natural Language Processing, pandas, matplotlib, python, Data Cleaning Deep Learning: TensorFlow, keras, CNN, faster CNN, RNN, RNN – LSTM Project Methodology - Agile Scrum

# **Programming**

Python Programming PowerShell scripting

Distribution: Cloudera

**Hardware** Nvidia tesla, Raspberry pi 3b+

Operating Systems Windows, Linux

Version Control GIT, BIT BUCKET

### Cloud Technology

Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform

#### Distribution

Cloudera

#### **Domain**

Analytics, Banking Telecom domain

- Hyper-parameter tuning to improve the model
- Validation metric for Regression and classification algorithms including classification report
- Participating in constant learning through training and skills development
- In-depth expertise with a rich repertoire of Regression, Classification,
   Clustering and Dimensionality reduction algorithms

# Hewlett-Packard – Senior Software Engineer Client: Ericsson – Telecom Domain

Bangalore, Karnataka

10/2014 - 06/2017

- Understand the requirements and formulate the problem statements.
- Acquisition and analysis of data
- Analyze datasets to provide insights to experts from various domains
- Building statistical modeling and applying various machine learning tech
- Data understanding and process formation from clients.
- Extensive hands-on with regression and classification techniques.
- Building baseline models for the requirements with necessary data prep

SLK – System Engineer Client: JP Morgan Chase (Banking)

Bangalore, Karnataka 08/2011 - 09/2014

- Worked with developer team to identify the use cases for machine learning in enterprise product.
- Experience in Data Analysis, involved in power shell scripting
- Fetching user data based on the application uses from the all zone APAC, EMEA, AMCS.
- After that by using excel we are visualizing the data and report to Mgr.
- As I do have knowledge on Citrix Virtualization, so I was bit involved in analytics division whoever using application via Citrix

# **Achievements**

Recognized for contribution of developing an automated chatbot concepts for claims part as cost saving project for a European Insurance giant.

Data Science Blog by me: <a href="https://datasciencecapsule.blogspot.com">https://datasciencecapsule.blogspot.com</a>

#### Strength

**Positive Attitude:** To progress positively under all circumstances with conviction and maturity in approach.

**Adaptability & Flexibility:** To adapt accordingly under the application of adverse or pressure conditions without deviating from critical to quality concerns. **Enthusiasm for Learning:** Endlessly strives to learn through different activities.

# **Certifications**

Data Science Master by INeuron.ai SQL for DS by Analytics vidya Data Science, Tableau, Machine Learning by- Simplilearn Python Certified by Devu.in Aws Certified Professional ITIL4 Certified by axelos

#### **Education**

2007-2011

Rajeev Gandhi Technological University, Bhopal MP Bachelor of Engineering (IT)

# **Training**

6 Months Data Science Master training by INeuron.ai

3 days Workshop on ML and AI by Harman International.

## **Personal Information**

Date of Birth - 01/04/1989

Marital Status - Married

Nationality - Indian

Linguistic Skills - English, Hindi

Current Location - Bangalore (India)

Mobile No - +91 - 9591030711

#### GitHub link

https://github.com/anandkashyap4711

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anand-kashyap-7295042b/

# Kaggle

https://www.kaggle.com/anandkashyap